[
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the origin and evolution of local early-type galaxies exhibiting dust features and the nature of AGN activity in these galaxies.",
        "Solution": "Analyzing optical and radio data, and comparing these with a control sample.",
        "Methodology": "The study was conducted by examining the AGN activity in dust lane early-type galaxies and comparing it to a control sample. The distribution of AGN properties in different environments was also assessed.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation was based on the likelihood of dust lane early-type galaxies to host emission-line AGN compared to the control sample, the correlation between radio and emission-line AGN activity, and the distribution of AGN properties in different environments.",
        "Results": "The study concluded that dust lane early-type galaxies are starburst systems formed in gas-rich mergers, representing an evolutionary stage between starbursting and quiescent galaxies. In these galaxies, the AGN has already been triggered but has not yet completely destroyed the gas reservoir required for star formation."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the number of independent dimensions of the space defined by stellar chemical element abundances [X/Fe] and the patterns of element production in various star types and galaxies.",
        "Solution": "Perform a chemical tagging survey of about a million Galactic FGK stars and analyze the results.",
        "Methodology": "Explore abundances in various environments, including different types of stars and galaxies. Analyze the patterns of element production, especially at different metallicities.",
        "Evaluation": "Compare the estimated number of independent dimensions of the chemical space in the solar neighbourhood and in fainter galaxies, and assess the implications of the findings.",
        "Results": "Two types of core-collapse supernovae have been identified, a consistent number of dimensions of the chemical space in the solar neighborhood has been estimated, and a higher dimensionality in fainter galaxies has been observed, which is consistent with their slower star formation history."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the detailed elemental abundances of 12 subgiants in the open cluster IC 4756 and the variations in these abundances.",
        "Solution": "Using measurements of elemental abundances as a probe to reconstruct dispersed clusters and exploiting the production of alpha-elements for chemical tagging.",
        "Methodology": "Measurement of the elemental abundances of Na, Al, Mg, Si, Ca, Ti, Cr, Ni, Fe, Zn and Ba in 12 subgiants in the open cluster IC 4756. Identification of discrepancies between abundances of certain elements.",
        "Evaluation": "Comparison of the measured star-to-star [X/H] abundance variation with expected variation from a coeval stellar population preserving natal abundance patterns. Observation of discrepancies between Cr I and Cr II abundances and between Ti I and Ti II abundances.",
        "Results": "The cluster's [Fe/H] measure is -0.01 +/- 0.10. IC 4756 are supersolar in Mg, Si, Na and Al, but are solar in the other elements. The production of alpha-elements is suggested to not be one-dimensional."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The possibility of a repulsive gravitational interaction between antimatter and ordinary matter, and the idea of substituting dark energy with anti-gravity by antimatter.",
        "Solution": "A precise measurement of the free-fall acceleration of antihydrogen could definitively solve this issue.",
        "Methodology": "Experiments including the measurement of free-fall accelerations of various nuclei and searches for equivalence principle violation through the gravitational splitting in kaon physics, along with new theoretical developments.",
        "Evaluation": "Comparing the results of experiments and theoretical predictions against the idea of anti-gravity and the substitution of dark energy with anti-gravity by antimatter.",
        "Results": "Constraints have been established against anti-gravity and the substitution of dark energy with anti-gravity by antimatter. No difference has been found between the gravitational behavior of antimatter and ordinary matter."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Identifying stars born in the same molecular cloud using their abundance patterns as \"chemical tags\" can be challenging due to large overdensities in chemical space and the survey sampling rate of the underlying stellar population.",
        "Solution": "Strategic observational plans can improve these factors, making it possible to statistically reconstruct the slope and high mass cutoff of CMF and its evolution through cosmic time.",
        "Methodology": "The study uses a model with $10^4$ distinct cells in chemical space and $10^5-10^6$ stars in the survey to assess the possibility of chemical tagging.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation is based on the number of groups that are $5\\sigma$ overdensities in the chemical space and the contribution of the most dominant cluster to these overdensities.",
        "Results": "The results show that even large overdensities do not guarantee a single set of stars from a common birth cloud, with the most dominant cluster typically contributing only 25% of the stars. However, different CMFs imprint different degrees of clumpiness in chemical space, providing an opportunity to statistically reconstruct the CMF and its evolution."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The number of synthetic spectra needed for a grid grows exponentially with the dimensions of the label space, making it difficult to fit more than a few elemental abundances simultaneously. Existing shortcuts introduce unknown systematics and do not produce correct error covariances.",
        "Solution": "A new approach, CHAT, which uses linear algebra and an adaptive, data-driven grid to generate a sufficient stellar synthetic library.",
        "Methodology": "CHAT employs a convex hull to approximate the region where the data lie in the label space. Around each grid point in label space, an approximate synthetic spectrum is generated through linear expansion using a set of \"gradient spectra\".",
        "Evaluation": "Tests with mock datasets were performed to assess the effectiveness of CHAT.",
        "Results": "CHAT can reduce the number of required synthetic model calculations by three orders of magnitude in an 8D label space. The reduction will be even larger for higher-dimensional label spaces. The computational effort increases only linearly with the number of labels that are fit simultaneously. These techniques provide new opportunities to fit the full stellar spectra from large surveys with 15-30 labels simultaneously."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The existing approach to fitting model labels to observed stellar spectra is considered unfeasible due to the exponential scaling of spectral model grid calculations with the number of model labels.",
        "Solution": "The authors propose the construction of a Polynomial Spectral Model (PSM) for the model flux at each wavelength, which requires significantly fewer calculations.",
        "Methodology": "The PSM is constructed with order O. In practice, a larger number of randomly chosen models (around 300-1000) are used to create a better performing PSM. The PSM can only approximate over a portion of label space, which varies from case to case.",
        "Evaluation": "The effectiveness of the PSM is evaluated using the APOGEE survey. The approximation accuracy of the PSM is assessed by comparing the approximated flux and abundances to the exact models.",
        "Results": "The proposed PSM provides a good approximation to the exact spectral models across much of the APOGEE survey. The PSM approximates the flux to within 10^-3 and recovers the abundances to within ~ 0.02 dex rms of the exact models. This method allows for the simultaneous fitting of multiple labels of spectra and observational parameters."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the processes which trigger star formation and Active Galactic Nucleus (AGN) activity in gas-rich galaxy mergers.",
        "Solution": "Use of Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) as part of the mJy Imaging VLBA Exploration at 20cm (mJIVE-20) survey to observe and identify the radio AGN in a sample of 25 low redshift gas-rich galaxy mergers.",
        "Methodology": "The study uses mJIVE-20 detection, optical and UV photometry to identify and classify AGNs, reconstruct star formation histories, compare H\u03b1 star formation rates with integrated radio luminosity, and model the actual sizes of AGN-inflated radio lobes.",
        "Evaluation": "The radio AGN hosts are evaluated based on their star formation rates, VLBI and conventional radio imaging, and the extent of the AGN.",
        "Results": "Three radio AGN are identified, which are not triggered promptly in the merger process. The delay can limit the efficiency of feedback by radio AGN triggered in galaxy mergers. Radio AGN hosts have lower star formation rates than non-AGN radio-selected galaxies at the same starburst age. The actual sizes of AGN-inflated radio lobes may be larger than what can be detected with current observations."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The common perception that deriving more than a few elemental abundances requires medium-to-high spectral resolution to overcome line blending.",
        "Solution": "An efficient way to model the full stellar spectrum, even when fitting a large number of stellar labels simultaneously.",
        "Methodology": "Quantifying the precision to which the abundances of many different elements can be recovered as a function of spectroscopic resolution and wavelength range.",
        "Evaluation": "Testing the findings against possible errors in the line spread function and small radial velocity errors, and using data driven models for spectral normalization.",
        "Results": "The precision of elemental abundances is nearly independent of resolution, for a fixed exposure time and number of detector pixels. The estimates of most stellar labels are not strongly correlated with one another once the resolution is more than 1000. These findings suggest new possibilities for the design of large spectroscopic stellar surveys and for the re-analysis of archival low-resolution datasets."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The low-resolution spectra acquired from the LAMOST survey were thought to limit the number of elemental abundances that could be measured, reducing their usefulness for Galactic archaeology studies.",
        "Solution": "By using a spectral modeling method that combines a data-driven model with priors that the model gradient spectra should resemble ab initio spectral models, the study argues that low-resolution spectra can indeed enable precision measurements of many elemental abundances.",
        "Methodology": "The study measures the relative abundances of 14 elements from LAMOST spectra with a precision of \u2264 0.1 dex for objects with S/N_LAMOST > 30 (per pixel). The training labels for this method are sourced from the number of elemental abundances measured in the APOGEE survey.",
        "Evaluation": "The study verifies the claim by Ting et al. (2017) that low-resolution spectra can enable precision measurements of many elemental abundances by applying the method in practice.",
        "Results": "The study concludes that obtaining high quality/resolution spectra for a subset of LAMOST stars and then applying this method to the full LAMOST catalog will provide a sample with more than 20 elemental abundances, significantly increasing the sample size for Galactic archaeology."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Finding clustering reliably in a noisy high-dimensional space, such as the stellar chemical abundance space, is a difficult problem that remains largely unsolved.",
        "Solution": "The t-distributed stochastic neighbour embedding (t-SNE) method, which optimally maps a high-dimensional space into fewer dimensions while conserving the original clustering information, is proposed as a solution.",
        "Methodology": "The t-SNE method was applied to a dataset of 13 abundances measured in the spectra of 187,000 stars by the GALAH survey. The projection was made to a 2D space for easier cluster recognition.",
        "Evaluation": "The method was evaluated based on its ability to resolve clustering in chemical space alone, recover known open and globular clusters with high efficiency and low contamination, and relate field stars to known clusters.",
        "Results": "The method was able to recover 7 of the 9 observed clusters with minimal contamination from field stars and low numbers of outliers. It also identified two Pleiades supercluster members."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Identifying and characterizing spatially unresolved multiple-star systems in main-sequence stars.",
        "Solution": "A data-driven spectral model was developed to identify such systems based on APOGEE DR13 spectra.",
        "Methodology": "Binaries and triples were identified as targets whose spectra can be better fit by a superposition of two or three model spectra than any single-star model. The model was applied to an initial sample of about 20,000 main-sequence targets, identifying about 2,500 binaries and 200 triple systems. The model was also able to fit single- or multi-epoch spectra with composite models, making it sensitive to traditionally undetectable systems.",
        "Evaluation": "The model's effectiveness was evaluated based on its ability to identify binaries and triples, as well as its sensitivity to systems with long periods. The agreement between spectrally and dynamically inferred mass ratios for binaries was also assessed.",
        "Results": "The model successfully identified multiple-star systems, and there was excellent agreement between spectrally and dynamically inferred mass ratios for about 600 binaries. Full orbital solutions were obtained for 64 systems."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Distinguishing red clump (RC) stars from their less evolved precursors, red giant branch (RGB) stars, is challenging and has been the domain of asteroseismology.",
        "Solution": "The solution proposed is to use the spectra alone of the stars to predict asteroseismic parameters and distinguish core helium burning RC from other giant stars.",
        "Methodology": "The work uses a sample of 1,676 RGB and RC stars which have both single epoch infrared spectra from the APOGEE survey and asteroseismic parameters and classification.",
        "Evaluation": "The method is assessed by the ability to distinguish core helium burning RC from other giant stars with less than 2% contamination.",
        "Results": "The results indicate that the method allows for a clean selection of a large number of standard candles across our own and other galaxies from spectroscopic surveys and removes one of the primary roadblocks for stellar evolution studies of mixing and mass loss in red giant stars."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determining the abundance of oxygen in stars is challenging due to a shortage of detectable atomic oxygen lines in star spectra and complications with these lines.",
        "Solution": "Oxygen abundance can be determined from low-resolution optical spectra.",
        "Methodology": "The study investigates the spectral features that arise from both the CO-dominant and the atomic carbon-dominant regions in the atmospheres of cool stars, such as K-giants. Changes in oxygen abundance affect the abundances of carbon-bearing molecules, changing the strength of CH, CN, and C2 features across the optical spectrum.",
        "Evaluation": "The approach is evaluated by examining the effect of changes in oxygen abundance on the strength of spectral features and the abundances of carbon-bearing molecules.",
        "Results": "The study demonstrates that physically sound measurements of abundance need not be limited to elements that have observable lines themselves."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Strong suppression of star formation efficiency (SFE) in some early-type galaxies (ETGs) following gas-rich minor mergers, in contrast to common starburst phenomena.",
        "Solution": "Observation and analysis of six ETGs that have recently undergone gas-rich minor mergers and exhibit extremely low SFEs using the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA).",
        "Methodology": "Study of the morphology and kinematics of the molecular gas in these galaxies using the resolving power of ALMA. Derivation of high velocity dispersions and Toomre Q stability parameters for the gas through kinematic modelling.",
        "Evaluation": "Comparison of the galaxies to the Kennicutt-Schmidt relation for star-forming galaxies and the relation for relaxed ETGs. Estimation of merger ages based on observed disturbances in the gas distribution.",
        "Results": "Most galaxies showed spatial and kinematical irregularities suggesting dynamical effects stabilize the gas against gravitational collapse, potentially causing the strong SFE suppression. These galaxies lie significantly below the Kennicutt-Schmidt relation for star-forming galaxies and the relation for relaxed ETGs."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the structure in the planar (u,v) velocity distribution of nearby stars and how it depends on metallicity and viewing direction within the Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "Using GALAH survey data and Hipparcos observations to study the Hercules stream and moving groups in nearby stars.",
        "Methodology": "Observing the Hercules stream in higher metallicity stars and the moving groups in stars nearer than 250 pc. The viewing direction (galactic longitude and hemisphere) and metallicity are considered.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessing the visibility and peak velocities of the Hercules stream and moving groups in the velocity distributions. Checking if the gap between the stellar stream and more circular orbits is associated with a specific angular momentum value.",
        "Results": "The Hercules stream is most visible in higher metallicity stars with distance less than 1 kpc. Its peak v value changes based on viewed galactic longitude, supporting a bar resonant model for the Hercules stream. There is fine structure in local velocity distributions that changes over distances of a few hundred pc in the Galaxy."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Difficulty in accurately determining stellar ages and masses, as well as understanding the age-metallicity relationship in the solar neighbourhood.",
        "Solution": "A Bayesian method of isochrone fitting that incorporates parallax-based absolute K magnitude, differentiation between initial bulk metallicity and present day surface metallicity, and other available constraints.",
        "Methodology": "The method was tested by re-computing stellar ages and masses of approximately 4000 stars from six well-studied literature samples using both Hipparcos and TGAS parallaxes. The method was further evaluated by re-analyzing the Geneva-Copenhagen Survey with the inclusion of TGAS-parallaxes and initial bulk metallicity sampling.",
        "Evaluation": "The calculated ages and masses were compared with established literature values. The age-metallicity relationship derived from the re-analysis of the Geneva-Copenhagen Survey was compared with previous studies.",
        "Results": "The calculated ages were found to be compatible with literature values, but with reduced uncertainties. The age-metallicity trend for disk stars younger than 11 billion years was found to be flat, with less scatter at all ages compared to previous studies."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the co-orbiting nature of certain pairs of stars and the implications of their abundance patterns",
        "Solution": "Analysed the stellar parameters and elemental abundances of 15 pairs of stars using the second data release of the GALAH survey",
        "Methodology": "Identified potentially co-moving pairs of stars based on proper motions and parallaxes from Gaia DR1. Subsequently analysed their orbital patterns and elemental abundances",
        "Evaluation": "Assessed the co-orbiting nature of these pairs and examined their abundance patterns. Differences in [Fe/H] were used to infer potential reasons for their co-orbiting nature",
        "Results": "Found that 11 of the 15 pairs have similar Galactic orbits, with four not truly co-orbiting. Among the co-orbiting pairs, three showed similar abundance patterns, while five showed significant [Fe/H] differences, suggesting different reasons for their co-orbiting nature"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Observing and analyzing the spectra of 571 supergiants in the Magellanic Clouds, which are well outside the normal bounds of The Cannon's training set.",
        "Solution": "Use The Cannon, a data-driven generative modelling approach, to determine stellar parameter and abundances.",
        "Methodology": "The GALAH and TESS-HERMES surveys were used to observe these stars. The Cannon was then used to analyze the spectra of these supergiants.",
        "Evaluation": "The parameters obtained were astrophysically incorrect, but the $v\\sin i$ and the abundances of lithium, barium, and magnesium were excellent discriminants of these stars.",
        "Results": "The Cannon can be used to determine accurate values for these types of stars in the future with an expanded training set."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need for accurate radial velocities of stars for studies of dynamics within stellar clusters, associations and streams in the Galaxy and distribution of dark matter.",
        "Solution": "A large-scale magnitude-limited southern stellar spectroscopic survey called GALAH provides radial velocities with typical accuracy.",
        "Methodology": "Using a high resolving power, good signal to noise ratio, and large wavelength coverage, radial velocities of stars were obtained. Also, convective motions in stellar atmosphere and gravitational redshift were considered. Median spectra were derived from a bin of observed spectra with a certain temperature, gravity, and metallicity range.",
        "Evaluation": "The accuracy of the radial velocities was compared with the accuracy of velocity components along the sky plane derived by Gaia for the same stars.",
        "Results": "The accuracy of GALAH's radial velocities is excellent and meets the needs for studies of dynamics within stellar clusters, associations and streams in the Galaxy and distribution of dark matter."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Need to study the effects of mixing and internal chemical processing in open cluster members at different evolutionary stages.",
        "Solution": "Conduct an abundance analysis of seven elements in 66 stars of the open cluster M67 using high-resolution GALAH spectra and 1D MARCS model atmospheres. Use non-local thermodynamic equilibrium (non-LTE) radiative transfer for the first time for a large M67 star sample.",
        "Methodology": "Analyze the abundance ratios from the non-LTE analysis. Study the trends in the abundance ratios with effective temperature. Compare the results with recent stellar models that include atomic diffusion.",
        "Evaluation": "The star-to-star scatter in the abundance ratios from the non-LTE analysis is around 0.05 dex. This scatter is larger when LTE is assumed. Most of the element trends are flattened in the non-LTE analysis, except for Al and Si.",
        "Results": "There are systematic differences in the surface abundances between turn-off and giant stars. The trends are more pronounced when LTE is assumed. The trends in Al and Si can be compared with recent stellar models that include atomic diffusion."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The effective temperature distribution of stellar evolution models along the red giant branch (RGB Teff) is sensitive to various parameters, including the treatment of the surface boundary condition. There is interest in using observational estimates of the RGB Teff to constrain the mixing length parameter, a_MLT, and its possible variation with metallicity. The choice of surface boundary condition is somewhat arbitrary.",
        "Solution": "Use 1D MESA stellar evolution models to explore the sensitivity of the RGB Teff to the treatment of the surface boundary condition.",
        "Methodology": "Different surface boundary conditions were applied in the stellar models and their impact on the RGB Teff was examined. The models were then compared to stellar parameters derived from the APOGEE-Kepler sample of first ascent red giants.",
        "Evaluation": "The effectiveness of the models was evaluated based on their ability to replicate the properties of the Sun and the RGB Teff in relation to the chosen surface boundary condition.",
        "Results": "Different surface boundary conditions can lead to metallicity-dependent offsets on the RGB. Systematic uncertainties in the models due to the treatment of the surface boundary condition place a limit of ~100 K below which it is not possible to make firm conclusions regarding the fidelity of the current generation of stellar models."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Quantifying the global efficiency of radial orbit migration among stars in the Milky Way disk, and understanding its impact on the structural regularity of disk galaxies.",
        "Solution": "A model that parameterizes the possible star formation and enrichment histories, radial birth profiles, and combines them with a migration model.",
        "Methodology": "The model assumes that stars are born with an initially tight age--metallicity relation which gets scrambled by radial orbit migration. It is fit to the observed age--metallicity distribution of low-alpha red clump stars with Galactocentric radii between 5 and 14 kpc from APOGEE DR12. The complex spatial selection function is sidestepped and the considerable age uncertainties are accounted for.",
        "Evaluation": "The model's accuracy is evaluated by how well it reproduces the observed data, particularly the age--metallicity distribution of low-alpha red clump stars.",
        "Results": "The model shows that the global radial orbit migration efficiency in the Milky Way is \u03c3_RM8=3.6\u00b1 0.1 kpc, indicating strong radial orbit migration. It also suggests the Sun's birth radius is approximately 5.2 kpc. From this, it is inferred that radial orbit migration plays a significant role in setting the structural regularity of disk galaxies."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to identify and study the population of carbon-enhanced and carbon-enhanced metal-poor (CEMP) stars",
        "Solution": "Use the Swan bands - molecular absorption features of the C2 molecule and a spectroscopic signature of carbon-enhanced stars - to identify such stars",
        "Methodology": "Use of 627,708 GALAH spectra in combination with a supervised and unsupervised classification algorithm to search for carbon-enhanced stars. Further study of these identified stars for characteristics such as radial velocity variations and Lithium enhancement",
        "Evaluation": "Comparison of identified stars with those described in literature, and observation of their radial velocity and Lithium enhancement",
        "Results": "918 carbon-enhanced stars identified, including 12 already described in literature. Among these, most are giants and 28 are CEMP candidates. A large fraction show radial velocity variation, and 32 show strong Lithium enhancement"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the structure of the Galaxy's disc components and the distribution of stars within them.",
        "Solution": "Use of the second data release of the ESA Gaia astrometric survey and the high-resolution GALAH spectroscopic survey for analysis.",
        "Methodology": "The alpha-rich and alpha-poor discs were separated using GALAH. The distribution of stars was studied in the zV_z phase plane for both V_phi and V_R. Simulations of tidal disturbance of the Galactic disc by the Sagittarius (Sgr) dwarf were presented.",
        "Evaluation": "The phase spiral, a signature of corrugated waves that propagate through the disc, was identified and analyzed. The radially asymmetric distribution of stars involved in the phase spiral was studied revealing that the corrugation grows in z-amplitude with increasing radius.",
        "Results": "The phase spiral likely extends beyond the narrow solar neighbourhood cylinder. The effect of tidal disturbance on the zV_z phase plane lasts >2 Gyr but a subsequent disc crossing wipes out the structure. The phase spiral was excited < 0.5 Gyr ago by an object like Sgr."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The observed structure in the Galactic disk has been mostly limited to bound clusters and moving groups. The combined phase and chemical space is expected to have a lot of structure due to the clustered nature of star formation.",
        "Solution": "A new dynamical model of the Galactic disk is introduced which takes into account the clustered nature of star formation.",
        "Methodology": "The model predicts the combined phase and chemical space to be rich in substructure. It evolves 4 billion stars over the last 5 billion years in a realistic potential including several components like an axisymmetric component, a bar, spiral arms, and giant molecular clouds. All stars are born in clusters with a range of initial conditions. The model uses a method of initializing star cluster particles to mimic the effects of direct N-body effects, while the actual integrations are treated as test particles within the analytic potential.",
        "Evaluation": "The effectiveness of identifying truly co-natal populations using the combined chemical and phase space information is demonstrated. Criterias like velocity separation < 2 km/s and metallicity separation < 0.05 dex for co-moving pairs of stars being very likely co-natal are shown.",
        "Results": "The combination of chemical and phase space information is much more effective at identifying truly co-natal populations. This approach will be beneficial for revealing the assembly history of the Galactic disk using the synergies between Gaia and spectroscopic surveys."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need for unprecedented scale and sensitivity in spectroscopic surveys, as well as the detailed study and characterization of exoplanets, substellar objects, and various aspects of stellar physics.",
        "Solution": "The development and use of the Maunakea Spectroscopic Explorer (MSE), a facility dedicated to multi-object spectroscopy.",
        "Methodology": "MSE uses 4332 fibers operating at three different resolving powers across a wavelength range of 0.36-1.8mum. The fibers have dynamical positioning that matches the exposure times of individual objects. MSE will collect millions of spectra per year down to limiting magnitudes of g ~ 20-24 mag, with a nominal velocity precision of ~100 m/s in high-resolution mode.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation is based on the number of spectra collected per year and the precision of velocity in high-resolution mode.",
        "Results": "MSE will enable new discoveries and characterizations in exoplanet science and stellar astrophysics, including star clusters, asteroseismology of solar-like oscillators and opacity-driven pulsators, stellar rotation, activity, multiplicity, and the chemical characterization of AGB and extremely metal-poor stars."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need for a detailed understanding of the Great Andromeda Galaxy and its merger history.",
        "Solution": "Using wide field facilities for both photometry and spectroscopy to study the galaxy.",
        "Methodology": "Performing chemo-dynamical analyses and studying the star formation histories of phase-mixed stars accreted at early times, as well as stars in surviving tidal debris features, M31's extended disk, and intact satellite galaxies.",
        "Evaluation": "By gaining an unprecedented view of the hierarchical formation of the M31 system and the subhalos that built it into the L* galaxy we observe today.",
        "Results": "The study is ongoing, and specific results aren't mentioned in the abstract, but the expectation is a significantly improved understanding of the Great Andromeda Galaxy."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Identifying co-natal stars outside of actively star-forming regions and bound stellar systems is challenging.",
        "Solution": "Use of simulations and data from Gaia DR2 and LAMOST DR4 to identify and study co-moving pairs of stars.",
        "Methodology": "The simulations followed the clustered formation and dynamical evolution of 4 billion individual stars over the last 5 Gyr. Gaia DR2 and LAMOST DR4 data were then used to identify and study co-moving pairs.",
        "Evaluation": "The distribution of relative velocities and separations of pairs in the data was compared with the predictions from the simulation. Pairs were deemed to be co-natal based on their similar metallicities.",
        "Results": "111 co-moving pairs were identified in the Solar neighborhood, showing a strong preference for similar metallicities, suggesting they were born together. It is predicted that co-natal pairs originate from high-mass and relatively young star clusters."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determining the effect of non-local thermodynamic equilibrium (NLTE) on the determination of stellar parameters and abundances of Fe, Mg, and Ti from the medium-resolution spectra of FGK stars.",
        "Solution": "Extend the Payne fitting approach to incorporate both NLTE and LTE spectral models.",
        "Methodology": "The extended Payne fitting approach is used to analyze the spectra of the Gaia-ESO benchmark stars and the spectra of 742 stars in 13 open and globular clusters in the Milky Way.",
        "Evaluation": "The accuracy of the approach is evaluated based on its ability to accurately determine effective temperatures, surface gravities, and abundances of the benchmark stars and clusters members. Comparisons are made between NLTE and LTE in the metal-poor regime.",
        "Results": "The NLTE values are systematically higher, and the average NLTE [Mg/Fe] abundance ratios are lower compared to LTE. All clusters studied are homogeneous in Fe and Ti, with minor intra-cluster abundance variations. Significant dispersions in [Mg/Fe] are noted for NGC 2808, NGC 4833, M 2 and M 15. The NLTE analysis alters the mean abundance ratios in the clusters, but does not influence the intra-cluster abundance dispersions."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to answer key science questions in various branches of astronomy, improve proper motions of almost 2 billion common stars, and measure more stars in obscured parts of our Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "A new all-sky visible and Near-InfraRed (NIR) space astrometry mission with a wavelength cutoff in the K-band, that is broad and not just focused on a single or small number of key science cases.",
        "Methodology": "The mission will combine with Gaia to provide improved proper motions. The addition of NIR will allow measurement of up to 8 billion new stars in obscured parts of our Galaxy.",
        "Evaluation": "The effectiveness of the mission will be evaluated based on the number of key science questions it can answer, the improvement in proper motions it can provide, and the number of new stars it can measure.",
        "Results": "The mission can potentially reveal the heart of the Galactic bulge region and provide a dense and accurate visible-NIR reference frame needed for future astronomy facilities. It can achieve a greater overall science return by going deeper than Gaia and expanding the wavelength range to the NIR."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determination of stellar parameters and individual elemental abundances for a large number of stars using low-resolution spectra from LAMOST DR5.",
        "Solution": "A modeling approach named The Data-Driven Payne (DD-Payne) is used. It is a data-driven model that uses constraints from theoretical spectral models to ensure the derived abundance estimates are physically sensible.",
        "Methodology": "Stars in LAMOST DR5 that are in common with either GALAH DR2 or APOGEE DR14 are used to train the model. The model provides stellar parameters and abundances for 16 elements when applied to LAMOST spectra.",
        "Evaluation": "The typical internal abundance precision is between 0.03 and 0.1 dex for most elements, with 0.2 to 0.3 dex for Cu and Ba. The internal precision of temperature and gravity is better than 30 K and 0.07 dex, respectively.",
        "Results": "Abundance systematics at the ~0.1 dex level are present in these estimates, but are inherited from the high-resolution surveys' training labels. For some elements, GALAH provides more robust training labels, for others, APOGEE. The abundance catalogs are publicly accessible."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to identify new members of the Fimbulthul stellar stream and confirm its association with Omega Centauri.",
        "Solution": "Using kinematics from Gaia and data from the GALAH survey, the researchers identified two new members of the Fimbulthul stellar stream and chemically tagged them to Omega Centauri.",
        "Methodology": "The researchers used the kinematics from Gaia and elemental abundance space data from the GALAH survey. They specifically looked for metal-poor stars that are enhanced in sodium and aluminium, which are typical of second population globular cluster stars but not seen in field stars. They also checked for the s-process abundance pattern seen in Omega Centauri.",
        "Evaluation": "The researchers found no other stars observed by GALAH near Omega Centauri or the Fimbulthul stream that could be kinematically and chemically linked to the cluster.",
        "Results": "Two new members of the Fimbulthul stream were identified and chemically tagged to Omega Centauri. This confirms the earlier work and further links this tidal feature in the Milky Way halo to Omega Centauri."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the age-metallicity relationship (AMR) in stars and its intrinsic structures, and determining abundance ratio trends for different elements across time and different metallicities.",
        "Solution": "Analysis of a large dataset of 163,722 stars from the GALAH Data Release 2, focusing on main sequence turn-off stars and subgiants.",
        "Methodology": "Isochrone ages and initial bulk metallicities of the stars were calculated. The local AMR was studied along with the scatter when considering observed surface abundances. After correcting for selection effects, possible intrinsic structures in AMR were identified. Abundance ratio trends for 16 elements were presented as a function of age across different bulk metallicities.",
        "Evaluation": "The trends found were compared with previous studies based on smaller samples of solar twins. The behaviour of different elements over time and across different metallicities was observed.",
        "Results": "The local AMR appears to have intrinsic structures suggesting two star formation events. The abundance ratio trends for different elements varied: hydrostatic alpha-elements declined with time, explosive alpha-elements remained almost constant, s-process elements increased while the r-process element decreased. This favours primary production from sources with a short time-delay such as core-collapse supernovae."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the assembly history of the Milky Way by chemically tagging stars, assuming stars born together are chemically homogeneous.",
        "Solution": "Testing the assumption on wide binary systems and studying their chemical abundance patterns.",
        "Methodology": "Using high-resolution spectra from McDonald Observatory to derive stellar atmospheric parameters and detailed chemical abundances of 50 stars across 25 wide binary systems identified in Gaia DR2.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessing the level of chemical homogeneity in these systems, and comparing the homogeneity of wide binary systems with random pairings of field stars of similar spectral type.",
        "Results": "80% of the systems were found to be homogeneous in [Fe/H] at levels below 0.02 dex and were also chemically homogeneous in all elemental abundances studied. Wide binary systems are more chemically homogeneous than random pairings of field stars of similar spectral type. However, they can differ in their detailed elemental abundances at a level of [X/H] ~ 0.10 dex, suggesting chemical tagging can work on a broad scale."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The difficulty in cleanly selecting red clump stars due to their similarity in Teff and log g to red giant branch stars.",
        "Solution": "Use of asteroseismic parameters, \u0394P and \u0394\u03bd, for accurate red clump star selection.",
        "Methodology": "The study predicts \u0394P, \u0394\u03bd, Teff, and log g using data from 2MASS, AllWISE, Gaia, and Pan-STARRS. It presents two red clump star samples, with varying contamination rates and distances.",
        "Evaluation": "The study evaluates the success of the selection method by the contamination rate achieved, comparing it to that achieved using Teff and log g from low resolution spectra.",
        "Results": "The study produces a catalogue of millions of red clump stars, presenting immense potential for studying galaxy structure and formation history."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding how a star in the Milky Way's disk can be at a Galactocentric radius distant from its birth radius due to two effects: radial heating (\"blurring\") and changes in angular momentum (\"churning\").",
        "Solution": "A parameterized model for the distribution in the stellar disk that describes the orbit evolution for stars of age and metallicity.",
        "Methodology": "The model is applied to APOGEE red clump stars, taking into account the survey's complex selection function. The model assumes coeval stars were initially born on (near-)circular orbits, and with a unique metallicity at a given birth angular momentum and age.",
        "Evaluation": "The model's fit is evaluated by its implied changes of angular momentum and changes of radial action.",
        "Results": "The findings suggest that the secular orbit evolution of the disk is dominated by diffusion in angular momentum, with radial heating being an order of magnitude lower."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to understand the unusual optical variability, increased brightness, and subsequent dimming of the star V* CN Cha.",
        "Solution": "Using extensive archival data and new follow-up observations to study the star and consider different theories for the observed behaviour.",
        "Methodology": "The researchers used both old and new observations related to the star V* CN Cha. They considered the star's high amplitude optical variability, its increase in brightness by 8 magnitudes, its brightness persistence for about 3 years, and the subsequent dimming period. They also noted that the star's current brightness is mainly due to H-alpha emission.",
        "Evaluation": "The observations were evaluated against different theories to explain the star's behaviour.",
        "Results": "The researchers concluded that V* CN Cha is most likely a symbiotic system that underwent a long-duration, low luminosity, nova. This interpretation makes the outburst in V* CN Cha one of the lowest luminosity novae ever observed."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the timing of major events in the formation and assembly of the early Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "Analyzing the data from 11,000 main-sequence turn-off stars beyond the Galactic plane to identify chemically distinct groups and their star-formation history.",
        "Methodology": "The study uses well-measured ages, [Fe/H], [$\\\\alpha$/Fe], and orbits from the H3 Survey and Gaia. The stars are categorized into three groups: a low metallicity population, and low-$\\\\alpha$ and high-$\\\\alpha$ groups at higher metallicity.",
        "Evaluation": "The timing of star formation truncation in different groups is evaluated. The orbits of these groups are also considered.",
        "Results": "The high-$\\\\alpha$ group's star formation ended 8.3 Gyr ago. The low metallicity population ended its star formation 10.2 Gyr ago. Most stars in the low-$\\\\alpha$ population formed less than 8 Gyr ago. The results suggest that a satellite galaxy merged with the Milky Way around 8-10 Gyr ago, causing significant changes in star formation and galaxy structure."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The issue of globular cluster formation and the origins of significantly helium-enriched subpopulations remains unresolved in Galactic astronomy.",
        "Solution": "The predicted observational properties of helium-enriched stellar populations in globular cluster progenitors can be studied using model stellar tracks and isochrones.",
        "Methodology": "The study involves comparing the brightness and color of helium-enriched and helium-normal populations at a fixed age, stellar mass, and metallicity. The time-integrated shift in ionizing radiation and the Lyman-alpha escape fraction are also considered.",
        "Evaluation": "The brightness and color of the populations were evaluated in various wavelength ranges. The time-integrated shift in ionizing radiation and the Lyman-alpha escape fraction were also evaluated.",
        "Results": "Helium-enriched populations are expected to be brighter and redder in the rest frame compared to helium-normal populations. However, the time-integrated shift in ionizing radiation is negligible, but the Lyman-alpha escape fraction could be higher for helium-enriched stars."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the properties of red giant stars with high lithium abundances and lithium enrichment and re-depletion mechanisms in giant stars",
        "Solution": "Use of the GALAH and K2-HERMES surveys to observe and investigate these stars and their properties",
        "Methodology": "Use of stellar parameters from the third public data release from the GALAH survey, a Bayesian isochrone analysis to divide the sample into first-ascent red giant branch and red clump stars, and asteroseismic data from K2 to confirm these classifications",
        "Evaluation": "Comparison of the likelihood of red clump stars and red giant branch stars to be lithium-rich, investigation of factors affecting a star's lithium-richness, and observation of lithium enrichment patterns in primary and secondary red clump stars",
        "Results": "Confirmation that Li-rich giants are rare, finding that red clump stars are more likely to be lithium-rich, and identification of different lithium enrichment patterns in primary and secondary red clump stars"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The researchers are addressing the issue of understanding the peculiar surface abundances in over 15,000 metal-rich A and F stars that deviate from Solar abundance ratios.",
        "Solution": "The researchers propose that these peculiar stars' photospheric abundances could be a result of stellar internal evolution, particularly the competition between gravitational settling and radiative acceleration.",
        "Methodology": "The researchers identified these stars by their high [Ba/Fe] abundance ratios in the LAMOST DR5 spectra. They also observed the stars' distribution, rotational velocity, and abundance patterns to draw their conclusions.",
        "Evaluation": "The researchers compared the stars' abundance patterns with the predictions of stellar evolution models that incorporate radiative acceleration. They also used the large sample of Ba-enhanced chemically peculiar A/F stars to test the mechanisms that alter the surface abundances in stars with radiative envelopes.",
        "Results": "The researchers found that the peculiar stars constitute 40% of the whole population of stars with mass above 1.5M\u2299. This suggests that \"peculiar\" photospheric abundances due to stellar evolution effects are a ubiquitous phenomenon for these intermediate-mass stars."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The depletion and enrichment of lithium in the cosmos is not well understood. This affects our understanding of stellar and Galactic evolution models.",
        "Solution": "A large scale high-resolution analysis of lithium abundances in GALAH field stars is conducted.",
        "Methodology": "Over 100,000 GALAH field stars with varying effective temperatures and metallicities are analysed. The stars are divided into two groups based on the Li-dip. Trends in lithium abundance to iron ratio are studied.",
        "Evaluation": "The lithium abundance trends in both groups of stars are compared. The lithium abundance is also compared with the predicted primordial value from Big Bang nucleosynthesis.",
        "Results": "Both groups of stars show similar trends, but the warm group has higher lithium abundances. At lower metallicity, the cool group shows reduced lithium relative to the BBN prediction, while the warm group is consistent with it. This suggests the warm group stars might preserve the primordial lithium from the early Universe."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Identifying and understanding the structures within 50 kpc from the Galactic center",
        "Solution": "Use of a large sample of giants from the H3 Spectroscopic Survey and Gaia to conduct a comprehensive inventory of structures",
        "Methodology": "Collection of 6D phase-space and chemical information in the distant Galaxy, including new structures such as Aleph, Arjuna, I'itoi, and Wukong",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation of the structures was based on their [Fe/H], [\u03b1/Fe], and orbital parameters",
        "Results": "The halo appears to be built entirely from accreted dwarfs and heated disk, with stars born within the Galaxy making up a significant portion at certain distances. Two massive accreted dwarfs, GSE and Sgr, account for more than 80% of the halo beyond 15 kpc"
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The challenge is to precisely measure the stellar abundances for metal-poor, low-mass stars in galaxies beyond the Milky Way using spectroscopic facilities.",
        "Solution": "The proposed solution is to use the Cram\u00e9r-Rao Lower Bound (CRLB) to forecast the precision of these measurements, and to use specific spectroscopy techniques for the best results.",
        "Methodology": "This forecasting is done for 41 current and planned spectrograph configurations. Moderate resolution spectroscopy at blue-optical wavelengths is used to recover elements, and high-resolution, low S/N spectra are modeled with full spectral fitting techniques to get rich abundance information. JWST/NIRSpec and ELTs are used to recover elements for metal-poor red giants and measure [Fe/H] and [\u03b1/Fe] for resolved stars in galaxies.",
        "Evaluation": "The results are compared with select literature abundances to assess their accuracy.",
        "Results": "Moderate resolution spectroscopy enables the recovery of more elements compared to red-optical spectroscopy. JWST/NIRSpec and ELTs can recover significant numbers of elements for metal-poor red giants and measure [Fe/H] and [\u03b1/Fe] for resolved stars in galaxies. An open source python package, Chem-I-Calc, is provided to help compute CRLBs for spectrographs of users' choosing."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Mapping from large sets of imperfect simulations and observational data.",
        "Solution": "Use of unsupervised domain adaptation and transfer between simulated and observed domains.",
        "Methodology": "Construction of domain transfer pipeline with two adversarial autoencoders, a disentangling latent space, and a cycle-consistency constraint. A differentiable pipeline from physical stellar parameters to realistic observed spectra is also constructed, aided by a generative surrogate physics emulator network.",
        "Evaluation": "Potential of the method is evaluated based on the quality of reconstructed spectra and ability to discover new spectral features associated with elemental abundances.",
        "Results": "The method successfully impacts the quality of reconstructed spectra and aids in discovering new spectral features linked to elemental abundances."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The lithium content in red clump stars, which directly follows the red giant branch phase, is not well-understood and not accurately predicted by current stellar theory.",
        "Solution": "Perform a large-scale systematic investigation into the lithium content of stars in the red clump phase.",
        "Methodology": "Observations of hundreds of thousands of red giant stars were made and the lithium content in red clump stars was measured and analyzed.",
        "Evaluation": "The lithium content was compared between different phases of stellar evolution, from the red giant branch to the red clump. The results were also compared with existing stellar theory predictions.",
        "Results": "All red clump stars have high levels of lithium for their evolutionary stage, with lithium content increasing by a factor of 40 after the end of the red giant branch stage. This suggests a lithium production phase that current stellar theory does not predict. A new definition limit for lithium-richness in red clump stars was proposed."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the nature and characteristics of the tidal disruption of the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy that has created a stream of stars wrapping around the entire Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "Using data from Gaia and the H3 Stellar Spectroscopic Survey to identify high-quality Sagittarius members and analyze their properties.",
        "Methodology": "Identified Sagittarius members based on their angular momenta. Analyzed the metallicity and kinematics of these members and compared the results with simulations.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessed the metallicity and kinematics of the identified members and compared the properties of different populations of stars within the stream.",
        "Results": "Found a strong correlation between metallicity and kinematics of the members. Identified different populations within the stream, including a kinematically-offset diffuse population at the lowest metallicities, which is speculated to be the stellar halo of the Sagittarius progenitor system."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the chemical enrichment of the youngest stars in the Orion complex due to its non-trivial structure, dynamics, and age spread.",
        "Solution": "Testing the hypothesis that early core-collapse supernovae can be observed in the chemical enrichment of the youngest stars in the Orion complex.",
        "Methodology": "Obtaining spectra of 794 Orion complex stars using the HERMES spectrograph at the Anglo Australian telescope, and using the spectra of 300 stars to derive the atmospheric parameters and chemical abundances of 25 elements for 15 stellar clusters in the Orion complex.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessing the chemical homogeneity of the Orion complex and the presence or absence of self-pollution of young clusters by core-collapse supernovae from older clusters.",
        "Results": "The Orion complex is chemically homogeneous with no evidence of self-pollution of young clusters by core-collapse supernovae from older clusters. The supernova rate in the Orion complex was likely very low, possibly producing no supernova by the time the youngest observed stars formed (from around 21 to 8 Myr ago)."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the chemical distribution throughout the Galactic disk and the history of our own Galaxy's disk using open clusters as tracers.",
        "Solution": "Performing a membership analysis based on Gaia astrometry to observe the members of potential clusters and study their chemical composition.",
        "Methodology": "Out of the 226 potential clusters falling in the footprint of GALAH or APOGEE, 205 were found to have secure members. High-quality spectroscopic data from the members of 134 clusters were analyzed to determine the chemical composition of 21 elements.",
        "Evaluation": "The radial metallicity gradient and the gradient in the [Fe/H] - guiding radius (rguid) plane obtained from the analysis were compared with previous works. The age-metallicity relation of open clusters at a given radius was compared with field stars.",
        "Results": "Open clusters trace the distribution of chemical elements throughout the Galactic disk differently than field stars. The differences are suggested to be due to the physical selection effect imposed by our Galaxy. Trends in the [X/Fe]\u2212rguid\u2212age space were revealed which are important to understand production rates of different elements as a function of space and time."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to recover the gravitational potential field to determine the spatial distribution of matter in the Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "A new method to find the gravitational field from stars' positions, using few assumptions.",
        "Methodology": "First, train a normalizing flow on sample star positions to get an approximation of the distribution function. Then, use the collisionless Boltzmann equation and a neural network to find the gravitational potential.",
        "Evaluation": "Comparing the flexibility of this new method to older methods that only fit specific models.",
        "Results": "This method could help us understand the density of the Milky Way using upcoming star movement data."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determining the characteristics and origins of certain stars in the H3 survey that are located near the tip of the trailing gaseous Magellanic Stream.",
        "Solution": "Identified the stars as debris from past Magellanic Cloud encounters.",
        "Methodology": "The stars were identified through their Galactocentric velocities and distances, and [Fe/H] consistency. They were also associated with the MS and H I compact clouds in the same region, both in position and velocity space, and potentially correspond with tidal debris in a published simulation.",
        "Evaluation": "The stars were evaluated on their statistical significance, their association with the MS and H I compact clouds, their potential correspondence with tidal debris in a simulation, and their provision of unique constraints on the interaction.",
        "Results": "The 15 stars represent a unique portion of the Milky Way's outer halo phase space distribution function, confirming that unrelaxed structure can be detected even at radii where H3 includes only a few hundred stars. They are likely debris of past Magellanic Cloud encounters."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The paper aims to identify and study high velocity star candidates (HiVelSCs), their physical properties, and their origins.",
        "Solution": "The solution was to identify HiVelSCs from the Large Sky Area Multi-object Fiber Spectroscopic Telescope and the second Gaia data release data, and further analyze their properties and origins.",
        "Methodology": "The methodology involved selecting HiVelSCs with three-dimensional velocities larger than 445 km/s in the Galactic rest-frame. The selected HiVelSCs were then analyzed for their metallicities and other physical parameters. The origins of the HiVelSCs were investigated through orbit integrations, and they were classified into four types.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation was based on the escape probabilities of the HiVelSCs, their metallicities, and their orbital properties. The evaluation also considered the potential parallax zero-point error.",
        "Results": "The study identified 591 HiVelSCs. At least 43 HiVelSCs are unbound to the Galaxy with escape probabilities over 50%. Most HiVelSCs are metal-poor and slightly alpha-enhanced inner halo stars. The study suggests that the majority of the stellar halo was formed from the accretion and tidal disruption of satellite galaxies."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the origins and properties of very metal-poor (VMP) stars to gain insights into the early stages of galaxy formation and assembly.",
        "Solution": "Use data from the H3 Spectroscopic Survey and Gaia to measure the metallicities, abundances of \u03b1 elements, stellar ages, and orbital properties of a sample of VMP stars.",
        "Methodology": "Use of spectroscopic survey data and Gaia data to analyze a sample of 482 VMP stars. Measurement of metallicities, \u03b1 element abundances, stellar ages, and orbital properties of these stars.",
        "Evaluation": "Analysis of the distribution of prograde orbits among VMP stars and comparison with expected isotropic distribution. Age estimates based on isochrones for main sequence turn-off stars.",
        "Results": "Most VMP stars are found on prograde orbits. VMP stars are uniformly old, suggesting they did not originate from the same well-mixed gas disk. The Galaxy has had a quiet merging history and its angular momentum alignment has been stable for at least 12 billion years."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Need for a detailed survey of high resolution stellar spectra, understanding the variations of individual spectral lines with stellar parameters, and assessing dynamics within streams and clusters.",
        "Solution": "The implementation of the GALAH+ survey, which provides high-resolution spectral data and new derivations of stellar parameters and chemical abundances. The use of Gaia data for studying dynamics within streams and clusters.",
        "Methodology": "GALAH+ used the HERMES spectrograph at the Australian Astronomical Observatory. It identified stars with variable and constant velocities. It also used Gaia data to study dynamics within streams and clusters.",
        "Evaluation": "The radial velocities derived from GALAH+ were compared with those from the Gaia DR2 or APOGEE DR16 surveys. The total mass of the open cluster M67 was also estimated.",
        "Results": "The study provided a comprehensive library of observed spectra and useful data on stellar parameters and chemical abundances. It enabled the study of dynamics within streams and clusters and estimated the mass of M67. The outer parts of M67 seem to be expanding, but further studies are needed to confirm this."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to search for stellar substructure in data from the ESA Gaia mission and deep photometric surveys to find evidence of individual accretion events that built up the Milky Way.",
        "Solution": "Identified a newly discovered feature, Nyx, which was initially announced as an accreted stellar stream.",
        "Methodology": "Used elemental abundances and stellar parameters from the GALAH and APOGEE surveys to study Nyx. Compared the abundances of the most likely Nyx members with the thick disk of the Milky Way and a dwarf galaxy.",
        "Evaluation": "The abundances of the most probable Nyx members were found to be consistent with the thick disk of the Milky Way, and inconsistent with a dwarf galaxy.",
        "Results": "The postulated Nyx stream is likely a high-velocity component of the Milky Way's thick disk. Emphasizes the importance of confirming findings across multiple data dimensions due to the increased probability of detecting coincidental associations with larger data sets."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the abundance patterns in Milky Way disk stars and discovering chemically distinctive stars and stellar populations.",
        "Solution": "Applying a novel statistical analysis to measurements of elemental abundances in these stars, fitting the data with a 2-process model, and computing the residuals.",
        "Methodology": "The 2-process model decomposes abundance patterns into a \"prompt\" component tracing core collapse supernovae and a \"delayed\" component tracing Type Ia supernovae. The amplitudes of these components were fit for each star, and the residuals from this fit were computed.",
        "Evaluation": "The residuals reveal a complex structure, including two correlated element groups. Stars poorly fit by the model help identify physical outliers and measurement errors.",
        "Results": "The abundance patterns in the outer disk are nearly the same as those in the main disk. Depressions of elements are found in LMC and Gaia Sausage/Enceladus stars, and large deviations are found in omega Cen."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "A group of high-mass, high-alpha stars appear young, which contradicts established understanding of the Milky Way's chemical evolution.",
        "Solution": "The researchers propose that these stars are actually old, but gained elements from AGB companions through binary evolution, making them appear young.",
        "Methodology": "The research team examined the chemistry and movement of these stars using data from the LAMOST spectroscopic surveys. They compared the stars' element abundances and movements to those of known old, high-alpha stars in the Milky Way's thick disk.",
        "Evaluation": "The researchers evaluated their proposal by comparing element abundances and kinematics of these stars to those of known old, high-alpha stars. They further assessed whether the stars have higher ratios of certain elements, which would suggest they gained these elements from AGB companions.",
        "Results": "The researchers found that these high-mass stars do indeed align with the old, high-alpha population in the Milky Way's thick disk. Some of these stars show higher ratios of certain elements, supporting the proposal that they gained these elements through binary evolution. This larger sample size confirms previous findings that most, if not all, high-alpha stars in the Milky Way's disk are old."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the formation and evolution of wide binaries in different environments of the Milky Way is challenging.",
        "Solution": "The problem is addressed by comparing wide binaries in the disk and halo of the Milky Way using data from the Gaia Early Data Release 3 and H3 survey.",
        "Methodology": "A search for resolved wide binary companions is conducted in the H3 survey, a spectroscopic survey that has compiled about 150,000 spectra for thick-disk and halo stars. 800 high-confidence wide binaries and two resolved triples are identified. Their binary separations, metallicity, association with the accreted Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus galaxy, and $\\alpha$-captured abundance are considered.",
        "Evaluation": "The wide binary fraction in the thick disk and the halo is compared. The dependence of the wide binary fraction on the iron abundance and the $\\alpha$-captured abundance is assessed.",
        "Results": "The fraction of wide binaries in the thick disk decreases toward the low metallicity end. The halo wide binary fraction is consistent with the thick-disk stars at a fixed [Fe/H]. The wide binary fraction is mainly determined by the iron abundance, not the disk or halo origin nor the $\\alpha$-captured abundance. The formation environments play a major role for the wide binary fraction."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determining whether unmixed merger debris (from Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus) could have persisted in the Galactic halo for billions of years and the implications of halo-disk misalignment in modern cosmological simulations.",
        "Solution": "Using a simulated stellar halo model to study the effects of different halo potentials on the preservation of the initial asymmetry of the merger debris and examining the relationship between the local and global stellar halo.",
        "Methodology": "The simulated stellar halo model was used with both spherical and tilted halo potentials. A realistic growing disk was also added to the potential. The relationship between the local and global stellar halo was studied considering a tilted global halo comprised of highly radial orbits.",
        "Evaluation": "The preservation of the initial asymmetry of the merger debris in different halo potentials and the impact of a realistic growing disk on the asymmetry were evaluated.",
        "Results": "The initial asymmetry in the stellar halo is preserved for billions of years when a tilted halo potential is used, even with the addition of a growing disk. This indicates the long-lived nature of Hercules-Aquila Cloud and Virgo Overdensity and suggests that the Galaxy's dark matter halo is tilted relative to the disk. The local halo provides a dynamically biased view of the global halo due to its displacement from the Galactic Center."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The 5th generation of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS-V) is focusing on stellar spectroscopy, particularly of the OBAF spectral types, for which no established survey pipelines exist.",
        "Solution": "Developing a spectral analysis algorithm, Zeta-Payne, specifically for obtaining stellar labels from SDSS-V spectra of stars with OBAF spectral types.",
        "Methodology": "Zeta-Payne was trained and tested on artificial spectra, and validated on two control samples of real stars. It uses machine learning tools and delivers only moderate internal uncertainties.",
        "Evaluation": "The performance of Zeta-Payne was evaluated by comparing the atmospheric parameters derived from high- and low-resolution optical spectra. Uncertainties in certain parameters were noted.",
        "Results": "The BOSS low-resolution optical spectra were found to be better for stellar labels of OBAF-type stars, unless they are highly extinct. The APOGEE spectra were less informative."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The challenge is to identify the birth of the Galactic disk and understand the early phases of the Galaxy.",
        "Solution": "The study proposes using chemistry, main sequence turnoff ages, kinematics, spectroscopy, and astrometry to solve the problem.",
        "Methodology": "The study separates in-situ and accreted stars based on angular momenta and eccentricities. It also analyses the behavior of high-alpha in-situ stars with increasing metallicity and their kinematics.",
        "Evaluation": "The results are interpreted using a simple chemical evolution model. The ages of the high-alpha stars are also considered.",
        "Results": "The study finds a \"simmering phase\" followed by a \"boiling phase\" in the early Galaxy, marking the birth of the Galactic disk at z~4. However, the physical origin of this transformation is unclear and not reproduced in current galaxy formation models."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The origins of Carbon-enhanced metal-poor (CEMP) stars are not well understood. Previously, studies primarily focused on the Galactic halo, with few studies investigating the thick disk and bulge components of the Milky Way.",
        "Solution": "Utilize $Gaia$ DR3 to provide a large sample of low-resolution spectra, and use XGBoost trained on the CEMP catalog from the SDSS/SEGUE database to identify the largest all-sky sample of CEMP candidate stars.",
        "Methodology": "Identification of CEMP star candidates was done by applying XGBoost to the CEMP catalog from the SDSS/SEGUE database. The $Gaia$ DR3 provided the necessary low-resolution spectra.",
        "Evaluation": "The results were validated by comparing with high-resolution catalogs from literature, resulting in a positive identification of 60-68% of the CEMP stars.",
        "Results": "58,872 CEMP star candidates were found, spanning from the inner to outer Milky Way. Future higher-resolution spectroscopic follow-up can validate the classification and further study the frequency of CEMP-$s$ and CEMP-no stars throughout the Galaxy."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Analyzing stellar light curves from the Kepler mission and inferring stellar surface gravity.",
        "Solution": "Astroconformer, a Transformer-based model that can robustly infer the stellar surface gravity and capture long-range information in time series.",
        "Methodology": "Astroconformer uses Transformer's self-attention mechanism, demonstrated through ablation experiments. It also utilises an attention map to illustrate how the model learns long-range correlation information.",
        "Evaluation": "Astroconformer was evaluated based on its ability to infer stellar surface gravity, its performance compared to other data-driven methods, and its ability to generalize to sparse cadence light curves from the Rubin Observatory.",
        "Results": "Astroconformer outperforms other data-driven methods and provides a more interpretable approach to asteroseismology. It can also be applied to sparse cadence light curves, opening up possibilities for a new era in asteroseismology with long-cadence ground-based observations."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Modeling quasar spectra in astrophysics is challenging due to the noise in quasar spectra and the need for predefined training continua.",
        "Solution": "The proposed solution is a novel unsupervised learning algorithm, Quasar Factor Analysis (QFA), which recovers the intrinsic quasar continua from noisy quasar spectra.",
        "Methodology": "QFA approximates the Ly$\\alpha$ forest as a Gaussian process and describes the continuum as a latent factor model. It uses unsupervised learning to learn the quasar continua and Ly$\\alpha$ forest simultaneously from the quasar spectra.",
        "Evaluation": "The performance of QFA is compared with previous methods in terms of quasar continuum prediction.",
        "Results": "QFA achieves state-of-the-art performance for quasar continuum prediction without the need for predefined training continua. Its generative and probabilistic nature enables understanding of black hole evolution and performing out-of-distribution detection and Bayesian inferences."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the origins and chemical makeup of the newly discovered high-energy stream, Typhon, in the Milky Way's distant stellar halo.",
        "Solution": "Analyzing high-resolution chemical abundances of seven stars in Typhon and comparing them with the characteristics of a dwarf galaxy and a globular cluster.",
        "Methodology": "The study involves assessing the chemical abundance, particularly \u03b1-element and r-process abundances, metallicity dispersion, and presence or absence of multiple star populations in Typhon. Also, it explores various scenarios regarding Typhon's possible origins.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation is based on the comparison of Typhon's characteristics with that of known celestial structures, and in the context of cosmological simulations.",
        "Results": "Typhon's chemical makeup is more similar to a dwarf galaxy, with high \u03b1-element abundance suggesting a short star formation duration. This finding is at odds with the typical characteristics of the distant Milky Way halo and suggests possible scenarios for Typhon's origin."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to understand the structure and evolution of the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) merger in our Galaxy's stellar halo, and its implications for dark matter detection.",
        "Solution": "Using data from the H3 Survey and a model of a general ellipsoid with a multiply-broken power law for forward modeling.",
        "Methodology": "Identified 5559 halo stars from the GSE merger using the H3 Survey. Used a forward modeling approach with a general ellipsoid that can rotate relative to the Galactocentric axes. The model also included a multiply-broken power law.",
        "Evaluation": "The best-fit model was evaluated based on its alignment with the observed data and its ability to resolve the debate in literature about the halo breaking radius.",
        "Results": "The best-fit model was a triaxial ellipsoid, tilted 25 degrees above the Galactic plane towards the Sun. The model included a doubly-broken power law with breaking radii at 12 kpc and 28 kpc. This model provides new insights into the GSE merger's initial conditions and evolution. It also suggests that the underlying dark matter halo could be tilted and triaxial, which has important implications for the Galaxy's dynamical mass modeling and dark matter detection."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Determining the kinematic structure of the inner halo of M31 and interpreting the galactic immigration history.",
        "Solution": "Utilization of DESI observations to study the kinematics of the inner halo of M31 in detail.",
        "Methodology": "Studied 11,416 sources in 3.75 hours of on-sky exposure time, out of which 7,438 sources were M31 sources with well measured radial velocities. Identified clear kinematic structures and compared them with dynamical models. Investigated the ability of the shells and Giant Stellar Stream to constrain the gravitational potential of M31.",
        "Evaluation": "The kinematic structures were compared with predictions of dynamical models. The consistency of the results with the interpretation of a galactic immigration event was assessed.",
        "Results": "Found evidence for shell structures in the Giant Stellar Stream, the Northeast Shelf and Western Shelf regions, consistent with a single galactic immigration event 1 - 2 Gyr ago. Estimated the mass within a projected radius of 125 kpc."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to estimate the ages of red giant and red clump stars and understand the chemical evolution of Galactic disc stars.",
        "Solution": "The Bayesian Machine Learning framework BINGO was used to estimate stellar ages and examine the age-metallicity relationship of the Galactic disc stars.",
        "Methodology": "Stellar age estimates for 68,360 red giant and red clump stars present in the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and the APOGEE-2 spectroscopic survey were obtained using BINGO. The denoised age-metallicity relationship of the Galactic disc stars was examined to identify chemical evolution patterns.",
        "Evaluation": "The identified chemical evolution patterns were compared with the patterns observed in the Milky Way-like zoom-in cosmological simulation Auriga.",
        "Results": "A drop in metallicity with an increase in [Mg/Fe] was observed at an early epoch, followed by a chemical enrichment episode. The patterns suggest that the last massive merger of our Galaxy, the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus, was likely a significant gas-rich merger that induced a starburst and contributed to the chemical enrichment and building of the metal-rich part of the thick disc."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Predicting the intrinsic quasar continua is challenging due to our limited knowledge. Existing recovery methods depend on a small number of high-quality quasar spectra, which may not represent the entire quasar population.",
        "Solution": "An unsupervised probabilistic model, Quasar Factor Analysis (QFA), which combines factor analysis with physical priors of the intergalactic medium.",
        "Methodology": "QFA models the posterior distribution of quasar continua by generatively modeling quasar spectra. It identifies latent factors that are more physically motivated than PCA. The generative nature of QFA allows for robust outlier detection.",
        "Evaluation": "QFA was applied to a large number of quasar spectra from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 16. It was evaluated based on its error rates in predicting continuum and in the 1D Ly\u03b1 power spectrum measurements.",
        "Results": "QFA can predict continuum in the Ly\u03b1 forest region with about 2% relative error, better than previous methods. It produced more accurate results for about 30% of the spectra where previous methods struggled. It also has a less than 1% error in the 1D Ly\u03b1 power spectrum measurements at z~3 and about 4% at z~2.4. It can effectively identify outlying quasar spectra."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The use of Machine Learning in astrophysics is challenged by issues of understanding, interpretability, and lack of proper training.",
        "Solution": "The authors propose a discussion to address these issues and suggest ways to advance the field.",
        "Methodology": "The authors have conducted a discussion session to address the identified problems.",
        "Evaluation": "Not explicitly stated in the abstract.",
        "Results": "The discussion led to the suggestion of ways to advance the use of Machine Learning in the field of astrophysics."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Previous studies on the Gaia-Sausage-Enceladus (GSE) merger, which forms the majority of the Milky Way's stellar halo, have mainly focused on the inner 30kpc of our Galaxy. However, simulations predict that debris from the merger could extend further out.",
        "Solution": "The researchers propose to study the outer halo by deriving metallicities and distances for a sample of luminous red giant stars and mapping the outer halo up to 100kpc.",
        "Methodology": "The researchers derived metallicities and distances for a sample of red giant stars using Gaia DR3 XP spectra. They obtained additional spectra of stars in two major overdensities, including the previously identified Outer Virgo Overdensity.",
        "Evaluation": "The stars in the overdensities were found to be relatively metal-rich and on predominantly retrograde orbits, matching predictions from GSE merger simulations.",
        "Results": "The researchers found evidence for a coherent stream of retrograde stars encircling the Milky Way from 50-100kpc, similar to the Sagittarius stream but moving in the opposite direction. They argue that these are apocentric shells of GSE debris, forming counterparts to the known inner shells in the stellar halo. These findings support the idea of an inclined, retrograde collision that formed our Galaxy's stellar halo."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the Galactic disk vertical velocity using different types of stars and how the vertical velocities of these populations vary with the Galactocentric distance.",
        "Solution": "Analyzing the Galactic disk vertical velocity using OB type stars, Red Clump stars, and Main-Sequence-Turn-Off stars, cross-matching these with LAMOST DR5 and Gaia DR3.",
        "Methodology": "The study cross-matched OB type stars, Red Clump stars, and Main-Sequence-Turn-Off stars with LAMOST DR5 and Gaia DR3. It then analysed how the vertical velocities of these three populations vary with the Galactocentric distance.",
        "Evaluation": "The study evaluated the results based on trends in vertical velocities, the bending and breathing modes indicated by vertical motions, and the warp amplitude for different star populations.",
        "Results": "The study found that the vertical velocities of these three populations vary with the Galactocentric distance and younger stars have a stronger increasing trend. It was also concluded that warp amplitude for younger stars is larger than for medium and older stars, indicating the warp is a long-lived, non-steady structure and has time evolution. The warp is also found to be lopsided with asymmetries along the azimuthal angle."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the origins of Ba-enhancement in dwarf and subgiant stars, and the lack of high-alpha Ba-enhanced stars.",
        "Solution": "Investigate the chemistry and kinematics of a large sample of Ba-enhanced stars with temperatures between 5000 and 6700 K, observed from LAMOST.",
        "Methodology": "Analysing the internal evolution process and external mass exchange due to binary evolution in these stars; identifying stars with C and N enhancement and ultraviolet brightness excess; comparing elemental patterns with hotter Am/Fm stars.",
        "Evaluation": "Observation of C and N enhancement and ultraviolet brightness excess as indicators of binary evolution; comparison of elemental patterns with hotter Am/Fm stars; identification of high-alpha desert in the iron-alpha plane.",
        "Results": "About one third of the stars are products of binary evolution; the remaining are likely created by stellar internal elemental transport processes; identification of a high-alpha desert, suggesting lower efficiency for producing Ba-enhanced stars by low-mass AGB progenitors in binary systems; calling for detailed modellings for these peculiar stars."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Understanding the radial metallicity gradients, azimuthal metallicity distributions, and their relation to high-velocity clouds, in the Galactocentric X-Y plane.",
        "Solution": "Use of mono-temperature stellar populations selected from a LAMOST MRS young stellar sample to investigate these gradients and distributions.",
        "Methodology": "Estimation of radial metallicity gradient, analysis of azimuthal metallicity excess distributions, and identification of potential metal-poor substructures.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessment of the metallicity excess distributions, the corresponding dispersions and the fraction of metal-poor stars in identified substructures.",
        "Results": "Identification of five potential metal-poor substructures possibly associated with high-velocity clouds. Observation of variations in metallicity inconsistencies with different stellar populations."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need for an efficient way to engage language models, specifically OpenAI GPT-4, with Astronomy papers.",
        "Solution": "The use of in-context prompting and a distillation technique that reduces the size of the input paper by half while maintaining its structure and semantic integrity.",
        "Methodology": "The model's responses are explored using a multi-document context, which involves ten distilled documents.",
        "Evaluation": "Assessment is based on how well GPT-4 provides detailed answers that are contextualized within the framework of related research findings.",
        "Results": "GPT-4 excels in the multi-document domain, with potential applications in hypothesis generation for the astronomical community."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Deriving stellar atmospheric parameters and chemical abundances from stellar spectra to understand the evolution of the Milky Way.",
        "Solution": "Use of MARCS model atmospheric theoretical synthetic spectra combined with a domain-adaptation method (Cycle-StarNet) and the L-BFGS algorithm to estimate the fundamental stellar parameters and chemical abundances.",
        "Methodology": "Estimation of the parameters and chemical abundances for 1.38 million FGKM-type stars of the Medium-Resolution Spectroscopic Survey (MRS) from LAMOST-II DR8. The surface gravities of the stars are constrained after estimating their bolometric luminosities using 2MASS photometric survey data, Gaia EDR3 parallax, and MIST isochrones.",
        "Evaluation": "The accuracy of the parameters Teff, log g, and [Fe/H] is evaluated by the PASTEL catalog, asteroseismic samples, and other spectroscopic surveys. The precision of these parameters and elemental abundances is assessed by repeated observations and validated by cluster members.",
        "Results": "For spectra with S/N ratios greater than 10, the precision of the parameters and elemental abundances can achieve 76 K, 0.014 dex, 0.096 dex, and 0.04-0.15 dex. For spectra with S/N ratios higher than 100, the precision stabilizes at 22 K, 0.006 dex, 0.043 dex, and 0.01-0.06 dex. The LAMOST MRS stellar properties catalog is made available online."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Accurately measuring stellar ages is difficult, and methods using chemical abundances may confuse star evolution with Galaxy chemodynamical evolution.",
        "Solution": "A probabilistic prediction framework for stellar ages is introduced which quantifies the contributions of both stellar evolution and Galactic chemical evolution.",
        "Methodology": "The framework is applied to both a simulated Milky Way sample with stars at various evolutionary stages and an APOGEE-mocked sample of red clump stars. It uses SHAP values to quantify contributions.",
        "Evaluation": "The framework's results are evaluated by comparing the influence of stellar evolution and Galactic chemical evolution on age estimates in different stellar samples.",
        "Results": "Stellar evolution is the primary factor for age estimates in the simulated Milky Way sample. In the APOGEE-mocked sample, ages are proxied through the chemical evolution model due to limited evolutionary information. This can cause deviations in estimated trends, like the age-metallicity relation."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The origin of two chemically-defined disks in the Milky Way and the alpha-bimodality between them is not fully understood.",
        "Solution": "A study of the chemical abundances in the M31 disk using JWST NIRSpec to determine if stars in M31's disk also show an alpha-abundance bimodality.",
        "Methodology": "Observation of approximately 100 stars in one NIRSpec field at a projected distance of 18 kpc from the M31 center. The 1-D extracted spectra were analyzed for metallicity precision, alpha-abundance precision, and radial velocity precision.",
        "Evaluation": "Comparison of the alpha-abundances in the M31 disk to existing models and the features observed in the Milky Way.",
        "Results": "No alpha-bimodality or low-alpha sequence was found in the M31 disk. The entire stellar population falls along a single chemical sequence similar to the Milky Way's high-alpha component. This could be due to M31's more active accretion and merger history."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Improving the performance of Large Language Models (specifically GPT-4) within the field of Astronomy.",
        "Solution": "Employ in-context prompting and adversarial prompting.",
        "Methodology": "In-context prompting is applied by supplying the model with up to 1000 papers from the NASA Astrophysics Data System. Adversarial prompting is used to further enhance the model\\'s ability to generate hypotheses.",
        "Evaluation": "The evaluation is based on the model\\'s ability to generate hypotheses after being exposed to specific astronomical literature.",
        "Results": "The study found a substantial improvement in hypothesis generation when using in-context prompting, further accentuated by adversarial prompting. This suggests a new way of using Large Language Models for scientific research in Astronomy."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "The need to understand stellar cluster formation through the analysis of stars' chemical signatures.",
        "Solution": "Application of the Weisfeiler-Lehman (WL) Graph Kernel to analyze a 15-dimensional space of elemental abundances and identify patterns correlated with cluster mass functions.",
        "Methodology": "Chemical distributions were simulated using normalizing flows to test the WL algorithm. The algorithm was used in conjunction with Gaussian Process Regression for pattern identification.",
        "Evaluation": "The WL algorithm was compared to deep sets and graph convolutional neural networks in terms of interpretability, efficacy, and robustness, as well as the number of required simulations for optimal training.",
        "Results": "The WL algorithm showed superior performance in all evaluated aspects and required significantly fewer simulations for optimal training."
    },
    {
        "Problem": "Training Generative adversarial networks (GANs) is often unstable and leads to mode collapse problems. This is a challenge in astronomy where GANs are used for creating emulators of numerical simulations.",
        "Solution": "The denoising diffusion probabilistic model (DDPM), which can generate high quality data without adversarial training, is proposed as an alternative to GANs.",
        "Methodology": "A comparison is made between DDPM and StyleGAN2, a robust type of GAN, using robust summary statistics from scattering transform. Both models are used to generate images of 21 cm brightness temperature mapping based on astrophysical parameters that govern cosmic reionization.",
        "Evaluation": "The Fr\u00e9chet Scattering Distance (FSD) is used as the metric to compare the sample distribution between the generative models and simulations. Fisher forecasts are also used to assess the performance of the models.",
        "Results": "DDPM outperforms StyleGAN2 on varied sizes of training sets. Unlike StyleGAN2, which shows varied types of mode collapses, DDPM yields a more robust generation. The diffusion model is thus a promising alternative to GANs for generating accurate images in the field of astrophysics."
    }
]